<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="layout.xml" type="text/xsl"?>

<page title="omniORB development" head="omniORB development" id="development">

<p>
omniORB development happens in Subversion. See the omniORB <a
href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/omniorb/develop">SourceForge
develop page</a> for generic instructions, or <a
href="http://omniorb.svn.sourceforge.net/viewvc/omniorb/">browse</a>
the repository.
</p>

<h2>Roadmap</h2>

<p>
The repository contains the following directories:

<ul>
<li><a
href="http://omniorb.svn.sourceforge.net/viewvc/omniorb/trunk/">trunk</a>
contains the current unstable development version. It is likely to
become omniORB 4.2.0.
</li>

<li><a
href="http://omniorb.svn.sourceforge.net/viewvc/omniorb/branches/">branches</a>
contains stable branches of omniORB. omniORB and omniORBpy releases
are synchronised with each other, so the branches are named after the
omniORB release.
</li>

<li>
<a
href="http://omniorb.svn.sourceforge.net/viewvc/omniorb/branches/4_1/">branches/4_1</a>
is the current stable branch, containing omniORB 4.1.x and omniORBpy
3.x.
</li>

<li><a
href="http://omniorb.svn.sourceforge.net/viewvc/omniorb/branches/">tags</a>
contains tagged releases. omniORB and omniORBpy releases are
synchronised with each other, so the tags are named after the omniORB
release.
</li>

<li>
<a
href="http://omniorb.svn.sourceforge.net/viewvc/omniorb/tags/4_1_5/">tags/4_1_5</a>
is the latest stable release, containing omniORB 4.1.5 and omniORBpy
3.5.
</li>

<li>
<a
href="http://omniorb.svn.sourceforge.net/viewvc/omniorb/cost/">cost</a>
contains testing code from the CORBA Open Source Testing project.
</li>

<li>
<a
href="http://omniorb.svn.sourceforge.net/viewvc/omniorb/www/">www</a>
contains these web pages.
</li>

<li>
old_* contain old branches and tags resulting form the conversion from
CVS.
</li>

</ul>
</p>

<p>
If you want the latest cut from Subversion without doing a checkout,
you can download nightly snapshots of the main branches from <a
href="snapshots/">this page</a>.
</p>


<h2>Building</h2>

<p>
Checkouts are built in the same way as a release. Note that to build
omniORBpy on Windows or other platforms using the traditional build
system, you must checkout the <code>omniORBpy</code> package within
the <code>src/lib</code> directory of an omniORB tree. With the
autoconf build on Unix platforms, it can be checked out anywhere.
</p>

</page>
