<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="layout.xml" type="text/xsl"?>

<page title="omniORB history" head="omniORB history" id="history">

<p>
omniORB was originally developed at Olivetti Research Ltd (often known
as ORL). It was initially intended just for use on small embedded
devices, communicating with commercial ORBs on desktop and server
machines. It soon became clear, however, that omniORB was better than
any of the commercial ORBs available at that time, so its use spread
to many machines and projects throughout the laboratory.
</p>

<p>
On 12 May 1997, omniORB version 2.2.0 was released to the world under
the GNU Library General Public License, ensuring its continued
availability to the CORBA community. You can see the <a
href="https://groups.google.com/groups?selm=3o207cznf5.fsf%40santaka.cam-orl.co.uk">original
announcement</a> courtesy of Google's USENET archive.
</p>

<p>
Over the years, Olivetti Research became first Olivetti and Oracle
Research Ltd (still known as ORL) and then, in 1999, it became
AT&amp;T Laboratories Cambridge. Throughout these changes, omniORB
development continued, with eleven public releases plus numerous betas
and development snapshots. omniORB is now used by many thousands of
developers around the world, and is deployed in countless
applications.
</p>

<p>
Many people have expressed surprise at how small the omniORB
development team was. The largest it ever became was five people.  The
following were part of the team at one time or another: Sai-Lai Lo,
Duncan Grisby, David Riddoch, James "Wez" Weatherall, David Scott,
Tristan Richardson, Eoin Carroll, David Evers, and Christof Meerwald.
</p>

<p>
On 24 April 2002, AT&amp;T Laboratories Cambridge closed as part of
AT&amp;T's global research cuts. With the lab's closure, omniORB
became an independent project, but several of the original developers
continue their involvement.
</p>

<p>
You can get more information about ORL, its projects and the people
who worked there at <a href="http://www.xorl.org/">www.xorl.org</a>.
Parts of the lab's website, including pages about omniORB, are
preserved at <a
href="https://www.cl.cam.ac.uk/Research/DTG/attarchive/">here</a>,
hosted courtesy of the <a
href="https://www.cl.cam.ac.uk/Research/DTG/">Digital Technology
Group</a> at the University of Cambridge Computer Laboratory.
</p>

<p>
omniORB is now developed and supported by <a
href="https://www.apasphere.com/">Apasphere Ltd</a>, a company founded
by Duncan Grisby. Apasphere offers <a
href="https://www.apasphere.com/consulting.html">consultancy
services</a> and <a href="https://www.omniorb-support.com/support/">commercial
support</a> for omniORB.
</p>

</page>
