<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="layout.xml" type="text/xsl"?>

<page title="omniORB commercial support"
      head="omniORB commercial support" id="support">

omniORB is commercially supported by <a
href="http://www.apasphere.com/">Apasphere Ltd</a>.

<h1>What is offered?</h1>

Support is primarily email based. The contract specifies a guaranteed
response time. When you send a query to your personal support address,
you are guaranteed to receive an answer within the specified time.
Often, the response will contain a solution to your issue, but in more
complex cases the response will contain an estimate of when the issue
will be resolved. You can choose a response time suitable for you;
most contracts specify 48 hours, but the time can be as short as 24
hours.

<h2>Email support</h2>

For most issues, email based support is preferable to telephone
support for two main reasons. Firstly, it means that the core omniORB
developers can deal directly with your issues, rather than being
several stages removed from telephone support staff. Secondly, writing
up your issue in an email allows you to specify the problem more
precisely than is possible with a phone conversation, which helps both
you and us understand the situation.

<p/>

Despite the advantages of email, it can sometimes be useful to discuss
a problem 'live', by telephone. We therefore offer the option of
pre-arranged telephone calls with an expert. This combination of email
and telephone support offers you the best possible service since your
issues are always rapidly dealt with by the most knowledgeable people.

<p/>

If you are using omniORB in a mission-critical application, emergency
telephone support can be arranged.

<h1>The omniORB advantage</h1>

Choosing omniORB gives you many advantages over other CORBA
implementations. Because it is open source, there are no development
or run-time license fees. Furthermore, support is extremely
competitively priced, so the total cost of ownership is radically
lower than for commercial products.

<p/>

omniORB is renowned for its robustness and strict adherence to the
CORBA standard. Independent tests have repeatedly shown it to have
significantly higher performance and smaller footprint than all of its
major competitors, both commercial and open source.

<p/>

In addition to the C++ ORB, omniORB also has a version for Python, a
high level, object oriented, interpreted language. Use of Python can
dramatically reduce the time spent developing prototype and test code,
and even large scale applications. omniORB's Python version is
supported alongside the C++ version.

<h1>What is supported?</h1>

Everything in the omniORB distribution, both version 3.0.x and version
4.0.x, is supported. All versions of omniORBpy are supported. Support
covers issues and bugs within omniORB itself, and basic help with the
details of the C++ and Python language mappings. <a
href="http://www.apasphere.com/">Apasphere Ltd</a> offers consulting
services for help with wider scale application architecture and
implementation techniques.

<h1>Pricing and more information</h1>

Pricing is worked out on a per-customer basis, depending on your
precise requirements. For more information, please contact <a
href="mailto:info@omniorb-support.com">info@omniorb-support.com</a>,
giving details of the support you require and any special requirements
you have.

</page>

